SERGIU GHENCIU

Software Engineer

About me

1024gs@gmail.com

+44 7454 026160

London, UK

10+ years of IT experience. I have got strong technical knowledge of JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, RESTful APIs, etc. I am creative, passionate, eager, and excited about what I do. I like new challenges on a daily basis and I enjoy my job since I have something new to learn each day about the latest programs and technologies in a rapidly changing environment.

https://rubymage.github.io

Personal skills



F

Languages

- Romanian: Native proficiency

- English: Professional working proficiency

- French: Willing to learn

Social

Good communication skills and flexibility in any circumstance, persevering, energetic, creative, team work abilities, leadership skills, resistant to stress

Fast learner

The ability to easily understand and learn fast, most of what has to deal with the digital world. Usually spending my personal time in learning new technologies and keeping up with the industry trends

Experience

Personal goal pursuit

Career Break - London, UK May 2023 - Present

Shifted my focus on studying and understanding the Bible.

Front End Engineer/Pod Lead

Masabi - London, UK June 2021 - May 2023

Worked on a cross-platform white-label app. Worked with different teams to gather the requirements and migrated some of the most important features to the new codebase. I then was given the Pod Lead role, completed the migration and delivered a new feature. I also worked with people and learned what were the challenges they faced regarding the release process and provided a solution on how we can continuously deliver a white-label app.

Achievements:

- Finished the migration of the app from v6 to v7
- Delivered the ABT Tokens feature
- Provided a solution to continuously delivering the app
- Learned the basics of Swift, Objective C, Java and took the ownership of the Capacitor plugin

Tools and technologies:

Angular, TypeScript, RxJs, Ionic, Capacitor, Cordova, iOS, Android, Jasmine, Jest, Nodejs, Bamboo Server, Swift, Objective C, Java

Staff Front End Engineer

Artfinder - London, UK July 2020 - Feb 2021

https://rubymage.github.io 3/8

Designed and implemented the dev environment for the frontend (monolithic-to-microservices migration). I then migrated artist and product pages to react while significantly improved the performance of the pages. In parallel I helped interview people and build the tech team.

Achievements:

- Developed a proxy server that allowed me to develop the FE under any domain name while pointing to any API environment
- Designed and implemented an API mock system that allowed me to speed up the development and also to easily achieve a test coverage of 70%
- Migrated artist and product pages to react
- Increased the Performance from a score of 44 to 96
- Increased the Accessibility from a score of 80 to 97
- Increased the Best practices from a score of 64 to 79 (third-party libs drag it down)
- Increased the SEO from a score of 75 to 91

Tools and technologies:

NextJs, React, TypeScript, Jest, Enzyme, Bootstrap, Python, Foundation 5, VueJS

Senior Front End Engineer

Simply Business - London, UK

Dec 2019 - 2020

The company wanted to migrate the FE to React but there was a long way to achieving that in my opinion. The FE development was still done in Ruby on Rails. I worked in a cross functional team mainly developing AB tests and also participated in discovery meetings providing technical support.

Achievements:

- Developed the unified-qcp AB test

Tools and technologies:

Ruby on Rails

Senior Front End Engineer

Amalytics - London, UK

May 2017 - 2019

https://rubymage.github.io 4/8

Worked closely with BA, BE and QA teams to understand the business requirements, to ensure a smooth integration with BE, as well as to fulfill the needs of QAs.

Main responsibilities:

- Ensured the technical feasibility
- Estimated the stories and contributed to the Road Map
- Decided which tools and technologies to use
- Designed and ensured the correct development and implementation of the application's modules
- Coordinated the frontend team in order to produce clean, maintainable and scalable code
- Ensured high performance on mobile and desktop
- Actively involved in problem-solving and actual coding

Achievements:

- Migrated the application onto the second version of the API
- Delivered CostLens, Remove Scenario and Migrate Scenario Modules
- Improved the appearance and responsiveness across all devices
- Improved the code quality by implementing ESLint and PrettierJS
- Decreased the build size from 664KB down to 257KB
- Reduced the deployment time from 5 minutes down to 24 seconds

Tools and technologies:

Functional Programming, React, TypeScript, Ramda, D3.js, Jest, Enzyme, Materializecss, SASS, Autoprefixer, Prettier, ESLint, Webpack, Docker, RESTful API, JavaScript, VanillaJS, AngularJS, ES2015, ES6, ES7, NPM, Babel, RollupJs, Polyfill, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Material Design, GIT

Full Stack JavaScript Engineer

Thirteen Elements - Chisinau, Moldova

Mar 2013 - 2016

Worked on various projects involving both, FE and BE and third-party APIs such as Facebook and Google login and posting on people's feed.

Main responsibilities:

- Produced neat code according to software requirements
- Designed and developed RESTful APIs
- Integrated with third party applications and services

https://rubymage.github.io 5/8

- Designed and developed intuitive, responsive and visually appealing user interfaces
- Ensured high performance on mobile and desktop

Tools and technologies:

MongoDB, Express.js, AngularJS, Node.js, Karma, Jasmine, Mocha, Chai, Elasticsearch, jQuery, Anime.js, Bootstrap, Materializecss, OAuth 2.0, Common third-party APIs, RESTful API, JavaScript, VanillaJS, ES2015, ES6, Material Design, NPM, Gulp.js, Babel, Webpack, LiveReload, ESLint, Useref, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Autoprefixer, Polyfill, GIT

Founder/CEO/Full Stack Developer

Casgon - Chisinau, Moldova

Mar 2010 - 2013

Designed, developed and launched a website that facilitated the sharing of lecture notes among students.

Achievements:

- Designed and developed the website, both, FE and BE
- Designed and implemented the database
- Tested and verified links and functionality
- Installed and configured the web server
- Deployed the website
- Increased traffic to the website via SEO
- Automated the deployment process

Tools and technologies:

JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, PHP, MySQL, GIT, Apache, Nginx, UNIX, FreeBSD

Founder/CEO/System Administrator

Casgon - Chisinau, Moldova

Dec 2005 - 2009

The company ran two activities, Computer store and Web & Gaming Cafes. Below, I am listing only those duties that I think have something to do with my career as a Software engineer.

Main responsibilities:

https://rubymage.github.io

- Designed and implemented networks
- Installed and configured devices (computers, routers, printers)
- Installed operating systems, games and software
- Diagnosed and troubleshot issues
- Controlled access to services
- Assembled computers

Achievements:

- Set up two Web & Gaming Cafes and ran them for seven years
- Assembled, sold and fixed computers for about seven years

Tools and technologies:

Windows, BIOS, disk image, game patch

Education

Master's Degree in Computer Science, Information Technology

Technical University of Moldova 2014 - 2016

Bachelor's Degree in Economics, Business Management

Academy of Economic Studies of Moldova

2003 - 2007

https://rubymage.github.io 7/8

Baccalaureate Degree

Theoretical Lyceum, Sciences 2000 - 2003

Sergiu Ghenciu - 1024gs@gmail.com - +44 7454 026160

https://rubymage.github.io